<?xml version="1.0"?>
<gameList>
  <game>
    <name>Ace Of Aces</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Ace of Aces is a 1st person, 2D flight simulation. You're onboard a British RAF Mosquito, maverick fighter bomber. Your mission ... stop enemy trains, intercept the terrible german V-1 buzz bombs, sink the german U-boats and down the Nazi bombers. Are you ready for this challenge?

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/ace-of-aces</desc>
    <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Imagineering Inc/Absolute Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Flight Simulator - Action</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Alien Brigade</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Alien Brigade is a side scrolling shooter similar to Operation Wolf. Aliens have arrived on earth and have brainwashed both soldiers and civilians in order to take over the world. Your job is to stop them! On each of the five levels you will have a different objective to complete, including saving civilians and destroying alien installations.

Throughout the levels there will be numerous aliens and brainwashed people you will need to shoot, as well as attacking tanks, helicopters, and more. After shooting enemies a bonus may sometimes be left behind; if you shoot this, you can earn additional ammo, more powerful weapons, or increased health. If you don't shoot fast enough and are hit by enemy fire your health will slowly decrease; the game ends when all of your health is gone.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/alien-brigade</desc>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sculptured Software</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Light Gun</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Apple Snaffle</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
A game that seems very similar to Boulderdash, but according to the author, "Its not going to be a clone of a certain well known other game involving rocks and diamonds. There are no enemies in this game apart from gravity!"

http://www.atariage.com/forums/topic/144344-apple-snaffle-7800s-25th-birthday-game/</desc>
    <releasedate>20100101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>GroovyBee</developer>
    <publisher>Unpublished</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Arkanoid</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Arkanoid for the Atari 7800!

http://www.atariage.com/forums/topic/154267-something-else-im-working-on/</desc>
    <releasedate>20100101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Propane13</developer>
    <publisher>Unpublished</publisher>
    <genre>Breakout</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Asteroids Deluxe</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
...It seems as though you've been here before - but this time, it's much worse! The Asteroids are faster, the enemy ships are much more skilled marksmen than your first time through this galaxy...and what's this odd hexagon-shaped craft I keep hearing about? Asteroids plunge at you! Trapped in a gigantic cloud of asteroids, your struggling spaceship hurls towards its doom. You'll have to pulverize all the asteroids with your photon cannon to save your ship and your life!

Rubble from an exploding asteroid bounces off your ship's hull. A glowing blur flashes across your viewing screen. So that's where the rubble came from! The asteroid was blasted by an Alien Robot Saucer! Alien Robot Saucers are also trapped in the asteroid cloud. And they fire at you! You know that the metal in your ship's hull will register on their target finders before the asteroids do. The saucers could be a worse danger than the asteroids! More rubble strikes your ship. Its hull rings like a bell. If you don't get busy, that could be your death knell!

Robert DeCrescenzo brings another classic Atari arcade game to the Atari 7800: Asteroids Deluxe! If you're a fan of the original arcade game Asteroids or its sequel, Asteroids Deluxe, you'll want to grab your joystick and start blasting! Asteroids Deluxe brings new graphics and gameplay elements into play, such as the Killer Satellite that when shot breaks into smaller pieces that take direct aim for your ship! There are also two new game variations: Competition Asteroids where you compete against another player for points (and your shots destroy the other player!), and Team Asteroids where you and another player share reserve ships and don't need to worry about friendly fire. Asteroids Deluxe for the 7800 is an extensively modified version of the original Atari 7800 game Asteroids.

http://www.atariage.com/software_page.html?SoftwareLabelID=2771</desc>
    <releasedate>20070101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Bob DeCrescenzo</developer>
    <publisher>AtariAge</publisher>
    <genre>Action - Arcade</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Asteroids</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Asteroids is a conversion of the popular arcade game. You are the pilot of a spaceship trapped in the asteroid belt, and you need to blast your way out! Each time you shoot one of the asteroids, it will break up into smaller pieces. Eventually the pieces will become small enough that they can be destroyed.

When all asteroids have been fully destroyed, you can move on to the next, more difficult round. Just in case the numerous asteroids didn't cause you enough trouble, a pesky flying saucer will appear from time to time and try to shoot your spaceship with torpedoes.

Hints:

1. Remember that, due to the lack of gravity in space, your ship won't stop rightaway, even if you stop thrusting.  If you need to slow down quickly, turn yourship to the reverse direction and then thrust in small bursts by tapping thejoystick upward.

2. The flying saucers can be dangerous, but they aren't all that smart.  They willsometimes run into asteroids themselves.

3. While hyperwarping can be risky, since you may reappear in the path of anasteroid, or lose your ship because of the instability of hyperwarping, itcan also be a lifesaver if you're about to crash.

4. It is possible to play the game just sitting still and turning your ship, butto get maximum points, you should learn to work with the thrusters your shipis equipped with.

5. Instead of randomly moving and shooting, learn to prioritize your targets.First, you should go after asteroids that are close to your ship and/orare in danger of hitting it. Second, you should go after any remainingasteroids that are onscreen.  Worry about saucers last, since while they do give good points, they aren't worth going out of your way for.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/asteroids</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>GCC</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Ballblazer</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Ballblazer is a one-on-one soccer match set in the future. You control a robot and try to snare a floating ball called a Plasmorb, which could then be fired or carried into the opponent's goal. You play on a simple 3d playfield which is split in half. You can play against the computer or against another robot controlled by a human player.

Hints:

1. Take the time to practice with the controls by playing a game against a low-level droid, or against a human player who is left idle while setting the clock to a high setting.  Learn how to shoot and steal the Plasmorb.

2. Over The Horizon (OTH) shots are difficult to pull off at first, but they can be done.  One suggestion is to aim at them and then pull backwards untill they disappear offscreen, then shoot.

3. If you've got an opponent on your tail trying to steal the Plasmorb, shoot the Plasmorb away from you.  The force will knock you backwards into your opponent, while sending the Plasmorb away from you, all while giving you the opportunity 
to recover it while giving you some breathing room against your opponent.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/ballblazer</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Lucasfilm Games</developer>
    <publisher>Atari Corporation</publisher>
    <genre>Sports - Soccer - 3D</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Barnyard Blaster</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
You and your grandpa just put your life savings into buying a small farm a few acres for growing vegetables and raising horses, a place to get away from the battle of city life. But you discover that the entire farm is full of things that are determined to drive you away.

Barnyard Blaster is a shooting gallery type game for use with the Atari XG-1 light gun or the joystick. There are three levels plus one bonus level.Your goal is to rid your farm of vermin by shooting targets in each of three levels.

Between each level you'll play Gramps' bonus screen where you can brush up on your shooting. But in order to proceed through each level, you must achieve a certain percentage of shooting accuracy. At the end of the game you're given a ranking depending on how well you did.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/barnyard-blaster</desc>
    <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Basketbrawl</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
In a desperate attempt to stop inner-city gang wars, the city leaders organized a basketball league. The league is scheduled to play on three courts: a street, a junkyard, and a rooftop. The mayor figured that a friendly game of hoops would be a much more peaceful way to settle disputes. He was wrong.

You can choose 1-on-1 or 2-on-2 game modes. There are six characters to choose from (ten in Atari Lynx version); each with their own health, speed, and power attributes. Each player without the ball can jump to block a shot or punch there opponent to get the ball.

There's also an option to perform a power throw on an opposing player. Players with the ball can shoot or pass. Power ups appear on the court at random instances. These power up one attribute for the player. For example, the lightning power up increases the player's speed.

The referee does not call fouls, but does hurl knives at the players.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/basketbrawl</desc>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>BlueSky Software</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Sports - Basketball</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Beef Drop: 10 New Levels</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Beef Drop is a port of the popular arcade game Burgertime, which Ken Siders first ported to the Atari 5200 and 8-bit computers. This version of Beef Drop beature POKEY sound support, for much better audio than the 7800 can produce without this chip. The 7800 version also features better graphics than the 5200/8-bit version, making the 7800 version the definitive release of Beef Drop.

The object of Beef Drop VE is to score as many points as possible by making hamburgers. To do so, Chef Pete must completely walk over each ingredient (buns, patties, lettuce, and more) in order to drop it to the next level. When all of the ingredients reach the tray at the bottom of the screen, the hamburger is complete! Assemble all four hamburgers to advance to the next round.

But in this fast food joint, the food itself can be fatal. While Chef Pete is scrambling to make his burgers, his mortal foes, Frank, Mr. Yolk and Dr. Dill chase him relentlessly. If any of them catch Chef Pete, he loses a life. If Chef Pete loses all his lives, the game is over.

Pete is not without recourse, however. By pressing either fire button, he can sprinkle a dash of pepper on his foes. The spicy substance stuns his foes for a few seconds, giving Pete a chance to make a quick escape. But pepper is precious, and Pete only starts with five dashes of pepper. Collecting an ice cream cone, coffee cup or french fries earns Pete one additional dash of pepper.

Beef Drop began life as an April Fool's joke in our Atari 5200 Forum and quickly turned into a real homebrew development effort! For all you wanted to know about Burgertime and more, please visit burgertime.info. We held a Beef Drop Label Contest to design an original label for Beef Drop, and the contest was won by Henry Lee. Henry's label design graces the label and manual, with additional artwork featured inside the manual. Beef Drop includes the cartridge and 12-page, full-color manual.

You can read more about how the 7800 version of Beef Drop evolved by visiting our Atari 7800 forum:

http://www.atariage.com/forums/index.php?showtopic=59998
http://www.atariage.com/software_page.html?SoftwareLabelID=2782</desc>
    <releasedate>20060101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Ken Siders</developer>
    <publisher>AtariAge</publisher>
    <genre>Action - Arcade</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Beef Drop: More Beef Drop</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Beef Drop is a port of the popular arcade game Burgertime, which Ken Siders first ported to the Atari 5200 and 8-bit computers. This version of Beef Drop beature POKEY sound support, for much better audio than the 7800 can produce without this chip. The 7800 version also features better graphics than the 5200/8-bit version, making the 7800 version the definitive release of Beef Drop.

The object of Beef Drop VE is to score as many points as possible by making hamburgers. To do so, Chef Pete must completely walk over each ingredient (buns, patties, lettuce, and more) in order to drop it to the next level. When all of the ingredients reach the tray at the bottom of the screen, the hamburger is complete! Assemble all four hamburgers to advance to the next round.

But in this fast food joint, the food itself can be fatal. While Chef Pete is scrambling to make his burgers, his mortal foes, Frank, Mr. Yolk and Dr. Dill chase him relentlessly. If any of them catch Chef Pete, he loses a life. If Chef Pete loses all his lives, the game is over.

Pete is not without recourse, however. By pressing either fire button, he can sprinkle a dash of pepper on his foes. The spicy substance stuns his foes for a few seconds, giving Pete a chance to make a quick escape. But pepper is precious, and Pete only starts with five dashes of pepper. Collecting an ice cream cone, coffee cup or french fries earns Pete one additional dash of pepper.

Beef Drop began life as an April Fool's joke in our Atari 5200 Forum and quickly turned into a real homebrew development effort! For all you wanted to know about Burgertime and more, please visit burgertime.info. We held a Beef Drop Label Contest to design an original label for Beef Drop, and the contest was won by Henry Lee. Henry's label design graces the label and manual, with additional artwork featured inside the manual. Beef Drop includes the cartridge and 12-page, full-color manual.

You can read more about how the 7800 version of Beef Drop evolved by visiting our Atari 7800 forum:

http://www.atariage.com/forums/index.php?showtopic=59998
http://www.atariage.com/software_page.html?SoftwareLabelID=2782</desc>
    <releasedate>20060101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Ken Siders</developer>
    <publisher>AtariAge</publisher>
    <genre>Action - Arcade</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Beef Drop</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Beef Drop is a port of the popular arcade game Burgertime, which Ken Siders first ported to the Atari 5200 and 8-bit computers. This version of Beef Drop beature POKEY sound support, for much better audio than the 7800 can produce without this chip. The 7800 version also features better graphics than the 5200/8-bit version, making the 7800 version the definitive release of Beef Drop.

The object of Beef Drop VE is to score as many points as possible by making hamburgers. To do so, Chef Pete must completely walk over each ingredient (buns, patties, lettuce, and more) in order to drop it to the next level. When all of the ingredients reach the tray at the bottom of the screen, the hamburger is complete! Assemble all four hamburgers to advance to the next round.

But in this fast food joint, the food itself can be fatal. While Chef Pete is scrambling to make his burgers, his mortal foes, Frank, Mr. Yolk and Dr. Dill chase him relentlessly. If any of them catch Chef Pete, he loses a life. If Chef Pete loses all his lives, the game is over.

Pete is not without recourse, however. By pressing either fire button, he can sprinkle a dash of pepper on his foes. The spicy substance stuns his foes for a few seconds, giving Pete a chance to make a quick escape. But pepper is precious, and Pete only starts with five dashes of pepper. Collecting an ice cream cone, coffee cup or french fries earns Pete one additional dash of pepper.

Beef Drop began life as an April Fool's joke in our Atari 5200 Forum and quickly turned into a real homebrew development effort! For all you wanted to know about Burgertime and more, please visit burgertime.info. We held a Beef Drop Label Contest to design an original label for Beef Drop, and the contest was won by Henry Lee. Henry's label design graces the label and manual, with additional artwork featured inside the manual. Beef Drop includes the cartridge and 12-page, full-color manual.

You can read more about how the 7800 version of Beef Drop evolved by visiting our Atari 7800 forum:

http://www.atariage.com/forums/index.php?showtopic=59998
http://www.atariage.com/software_page.html?SoftwareLabelID=2782</desc>
    <releasedate>20060101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Ken Siders</developer>
    <publisher>AtariAge</publisher>
    <genre>Action - Arcade</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>b*nQ</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
If you've ever played the 1982 arcade game Q*bert, then you're already familiar with b*nQ. Ken Siders has created a faithful reproduction of the popular arcade game for the Atari 7800 ProSystem. This is Ken Siders' second Atari 7800 homebrew written from the ground up. His first was Beef Drop, which is one of the most accurate ports of the arcade game Burgertime to any classic gaming system.

The object of b*nQ is to score as many points as possible by jumping on cubes, jumping on green objects, and luring the Snake to his death. When all of the cubes have been changed to the "change to" color, you will advance to the next round. After every four rounds you will advance to the next level. Later levels require jumping on cubes multiple times and the cubes will change in different color sequences, increasing the challenge of advancing to the next round.

b*nQ supports one or two players, so you can play alone or with a friend. You can select from one of four difficulty levels: Easy, Normal, Adept, and Expert, for greater challenges as you become better at the game. You can also choose whether your joystick operates in "rotated" mode (where you rotate the joystick 45 degrees) or operate it in "normal" mode where you use your joystick's diagonals to move b*nQ around the pyramid.

The label design for b*nQ was created by Darrin Rose, who won the b*nQ Label Contest held on AtariAge in November 2007. Not only does Darrin's winning design grace the label, but Darrin also created the b*nQ manual, which features more original artwork created just for the game.

http://www.atariage.com/software_page.html?SoftwareLabelID=2772</desc>
    <releasedate>20070101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Ken Siders</developer>
    <publisher>AtariAge</publisher>
    <genre>Action - Arcade</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Cat-Man</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
No information online about this Ms. Pac-Man hack.  ~Rx</desc>
    <releasedate/>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Maze</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Centipede</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
In Centipede, players control a magic wand that is used to square off against a horde of nasty bugs that make their way through a mushroom patch.

The Flea falls straight down towards the player, laying fresh mushroom in its path. The Scorpion runs from side to side across the screen, turning mushrooms into poisonous toadstool, which cause the Centipede to behave irrationally and dive bomb the player. Spiders jump up and down towards the player; the closer he is, the more points are earned (300, 600, 900) . And the Centipede makes it way down the playing field. Shooting segments cause the Centepede to split off and form multiple targets.

Shooting any bug turns it into a mushroom, which can block (or speed up) the bugs on the playing field. If any of the bugs touch the wand, it's lose a life until Game Over.

Centipede was created by Ed Logg, and used a trackball in the original arcade version.

Hints:

1. Don't let the centipede, whether whole, partial, or just a head segment, reach the bottom of the screen.  If it does, another head segment will appear onscreen.

2. Try to wait untill the spider is close to you before shooting it to earn the maximum amount of points possible.

3. Don't aimlessly shoot at the centipede, as you don't want to have to deal with too many head segments.  Instead, try to focus on shooting at the head instead of the body.  You'll earn more points that way, and have less pests to deal with.

4. If the centipede hits a poison mushroom, don't panic.  Try to get into position so you can shoot at it as it comes down towards the bottom.  You'll be able to earn a lot of points and take out quite a bit (if not all) of the centipede.

5. In Competition Mode, while it is fun to stun your opponent, remember that your shots can't kill them (this isn't a deathmatch!) You're competing for the highest possible score, so don't get carried away, or you may end up getting yourself killed while trying to slow down your opponent.

6. In Team Play Mode, remember that your shots can't hurt the other player, so don't worry about accidentally shooting them.  One strategy to try is having each player cover their own 'half' of the screen.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/centipede_</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>GCC</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Arcade - Shooter - Fixed</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Choplifter!</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Choplifter is a side-scrolling action/arcade game that puts you in command of an attack chopper. Your mission: Go behind enemy lines and rescue up to 16 hostages per level. Be careful, though, because tanks and enemy aircraft will try to stop you -- and they won't stop shooting while you are rescuing those hostages!

Originally released for Apple II home computers, Choplifter was later ported to the arcades and a number of video game consoles. Many imitators and homages would follow.

Hints:

1. The controls in this game are rather sensitive, so take some time to get used to them before you actually go into the danger zone.

2. Tanks can move very quickly, so if you see one, take off and destroy it with a bomb before returning to continue picking up hostages.

3. Jet fighters are extremely accurate with their missiles, especially when you're on the ground.  The best thing to do is dodge their missiles and shoot the fighters.  If you see one while you're landed, quickly take off and evade the missile it will fire, before countering with your own shots.

4. This game isn't easy, don't be frustrated if you can't get a perfect 64 the first time you play.  Be patient and don't give up.

5. And the one rule all chopper pilots remember when up in the air, HAVE FUN!

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/choplifter</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Ibid Inc</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Commando</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Several levels await your super-tough Commando in this arcade conversion. Armed with only a standard rifle and a few grenades you must take on hordes of Nazis. Some are wandering around in the open, while others have picked out hiding places, which you must approach from certain angles.

Trees, rivers and bridges create a varied combat-like terrain and must be incorporated into your thinking. Extra grenades can be collected, and will definitely be required, as they allow you to kill form distance and thus avoid some enemy shots.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/commando</desc>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sculptured Software</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Crack'ed</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
As a professional ornithologist, you're thrilled to find out that some rare South American hornbills have nested in your "old yolk tree." But while the hornbills are out feeding, a group of mischievous bluebirds, owls, and snakes begin raiding their nests and stealing eggs.

You get out your slingshot and begin hitting the marauding creatures. But you have to be careful. If you hit an egg-carrying bird, it drops the egg and you have to act fast to catch it before it hits the ground and return it to a nest. At the same time, you have to watch for snakes that may be sneaking up to nests and gobbling eggs. If you can protect the eggs long enough, you can take them to another nesting site.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/cracked</desc>
    <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Robert Neve/Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Shoot 'em Up - Fixed</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Crossbow</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
In Crossbow, you and several friends are trying to cross many treacherous landscapes in order to retrieve stolen treasures from the castle of the Evil Master. All of the members of your party are unarmed, however you carry a crossbow. Using this, you need to shoot any obstacles or hostile enemies that may get in the way of your friends as they cross the screen.

You see the landscape from a first person point of view, and one by one each member of the party will walk from the left to right on the screen. There are many different landscapes that need to be crossed, each with its own variety of dangers. There are deserts with scorpions, ice caverns, jungles with hostile monkeys, a lava spewing volcano, and even the heavily guarded castle. The game starts with two friends in your party, with additional friends joining after clearing certain parts of the game. The game ends when everyone in your party has been killed.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/crossbow</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Imagineering Inc/Absolute Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Light Gun</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Dark Chambers</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Dark Chambers is an arcade action game similar to Gauntlet. You are an explorer in an underground maze; your goal is to survive the 26 different levels and collect as many of the hidden treasures as you can. Hidden somewhere in each of the levels is an exit which will take you on to the next level.

Trying to stop you from completing your quest are a wide variety of creatures, including zombies, wraiths, skeletons, wizards, and the grim reaper. Each of the creatures in the game has a different strength; when you shoot a creature, it will transform into the next weaker creature. Eventually a creature will become the weakest one (a zombie) at which point it can be destroyed. In addition to the creatures and treasures, other items that can be found in the maze are keys (to open doors), potions (to restore health), poison (drains health), guns (increases your firing rate), traps, shields, and bombs. The game is played from an overhead point of view, and is for one player or two players simultaneously.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/dark-chambers</desc>
    <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sculptured Software</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Desert Falcon</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Desert Falcon is an arcade style shooter. Many of the Pharaoh's great treasures are lost throughout the desert, and your goal is to steal as many as you can to earn points. The game features a scrolling, isometric point of view as you control your falcon through the various desert landscapes.

The treasures you are after are guarded of course. Many desert creatures including vultures, warriors, flying fish, sphinxes and more will all attempt to stop you from succeeding in your task. Also, at the end of each level you will need to face a large, howling sphinx before you can continue on.

Your falcon isn't completely unarmed, and has the ability to fire darts which can be used to destroy the assorted enemies and the sphinx. In the sand, you will occasionally come across some hieroglyphs. Several different superpowers can be gained by landing and hopping over three of these hieroglyphs. Depending on which hieroglyphs are collected, you may become invincible, warp to the end of the level, earn free points, trick enemies into attacking a decoy instead of you, or even get an air bomb which destroys all airborne enemies.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/desert-falcon</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>GCC</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Shoot 'em Up - Isometric</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Dig Dug</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Dig Dug is a 1-2 player arcade game in which you have to use your shovel to dig your way through the earth. Stopping you from doing this are two monsters, called Pooka and Fygar, who will continually chase you around. The only weapon that you carry is an air pump, which you can use to inflate the monsters to the point where they explode. (if you start to inflate them but stop doing so, the monsters will get turned back to their normal selves.) Furthermore, rocks are scattered throughout the earth, and you can use these rocks to squash them.

If the monsters do not find you for several seconds, they will eventually get turned into ghosts, which are able to walk through the earth. They are invincible and cannot be killed. From time to time, vegetables will appear in the center, and you can get these for points.

Hints:

Continue gameplay - When you lose your last life, press Left Fire as fast as you can to continue playing the game.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/dig-dug</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>GCC</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Donkey Kong Junior</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Donkey Kong Jr. was originally released in the arcades in 1982 as a sequel to Donkey Kong. In this game, Mario plays the antagonist, finally having captured Donkey Kong, and has put the ape in a locked cage. As Donkey Kong Jr., players will have to make their way through four different levels (Vines, Springboard, Chains and Mario's Hideout) in an attempt to find keys to free the little monkey's Father.

Along the way, Mario will send out Snapjaws, swooping purple birds, and electric sparks in an attempt to stop Junior. Junior can defend himself by dropping fruit found around the levels on the heads of his foes. The more foes a piece of fruit hits in a falling sequence, the higher bonus points can be scored.

Junior can also avoid enemies more easily by grabbing hold of two chains or vines at a time to climb away faster, or by jumping over his foes. However, any long fall or falling into the water on certain levels will mean the loss of a life for Junior.

In the final cut scene, Junior will free Donkey Kong and both will escape after giving Mario the boot. Once all four levels are cleared, the game levels will start over at a higher difficulty.

Like the original Donkey Kong, the earlier 1980's console versions do not have all of the levels and animations from the arcade.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/donkey-kong-junior</desc>
    <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ITDC</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Donkey Kong</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Released in the arcades in 1981, Donkey Kong was not only Nintendo's first real smash hit for the company, but marked the introduction for two of their most popular mascots: Mario (originally "Jumpman") and Donkey Kong.

Donkey Kong is a platform-action game that has Mario scale four different industrial themed levels (construction zone, cement factory, an elevator-themed level, and removing rivets from girders) in an attempt to save the damsel in distress, Pauline, from the big ape before the timer runs out. Once the rivets are removed from the final level, Donkey Kong falls, and the two lovers are reunited. From there, the levels start over at a higher difficulty.

Along the way, Mario must dodge a constant stream of barrels, "living" fireballs, and spring-weights. Although not as powerful as in other future games, Mario can find a hammer which allows him to destroy the barrels and fireballs for a limited amount of time. Additionally, Mario can also find Pauline's hat, purse and umbrella for additional bonus points.

Donkey Kong is also notable for being one of the first complete narratives in video game form, told through simplistic cut scenes that advance the story. It should also be noted that in versions of the game for early 1980's consoles, Donkey Kong only used 2-3 of the original levels, with the cement factory usually omitted.

Controls:

Button 1 or 2: Mario jump.
Left and right: move Mario in that direction.
Up and down: climb up or down the ladders.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/donkey-kong</desc>
    <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ITDC</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Double Dragon</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Set in a post-apocalyptic New York, Double Dragon is the story of Billy and Jimmy Lee, twin brothers trained in the fighting style of Sou-Setsu-Ken. Together, they manage a small martial arts training school, teaching their students in self-defense. One day, Billy's girlfriend, Marian, is kidnapped off the street by the "Black Warriors", a savage street gang led by a man named Willy. The Black Warriors demand the Lee brothers disclose their martial arts secrets in exchange for Marian's freedom. The Lee brothers set out on a rescue mission to crush the Black Warriors and save Marian.

Using whatever techniques they have at their disposal, from the basic punches and kicks to the invulnerable elbow strike, as well any weapon that comes into their hands, the Lee brothers must pursue the gang through the city slum, industrial area and the forest before reaching their hideout to confront the big boss, Willy.

Hints:

- Alternate Ending -
When the girl comes down, as she gets to the floor press Up and the fire buttons on both the first and second controller simultaneously. When she moves, before she touches the carpet, press Up. If you've done it correctly you will see the girl perform another ending.

- Defeating the Shadow Boss -
Avoid fighting the Shadow Boss' companions during that battle. They will automatically disappear when the Shadow Boss is defeated. 

http://www.atariage.com/software_hints.html?SoftwareHintID=2
http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/double-dragon</desc>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher>Activision</publisher>
    <genre>Beat 'em Up</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>F-18 Hornet</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
F-18 Hornet is a one-player fighter simulator in which the player pilots a Navy F-18/A Jet through a series of simulated combat situations including carrier take-offs and landings, bombings, strafings, and air combat.

In each of four missions, you are confronted with a variety of opponents and must perform a series of combat objectives in order from the Naval Aviator rank. 

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/f-18-hornet</desc>
    <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Imagineering Inc/Absolute Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Absolute Entertainment</publisher>
    <genre>Flight Simulator</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>FailSafe</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
After the successful elimination of the terrorists and their missile silo complexes, we have heard through various sources that they have relocated, and have doubled their security!  Once again you must invade enemy territory and prevent the missile launching aimed at Washington D.C. and stop the terrorists once and for all!

Failsafe is a sequel to the Atari 5200 game Countermeasure. Failsafe was called Countermeasure 2 before the author was asked to change the name.

The author that is doing this game is also responsible for Space Invaders, Space Duel, Asteroids Deluxe, Pac-man Collection, Jr. Pac-man, and Super Pac-man.

The author said the differences between Countermeasure and Failsafe are the following:

This game is 'destination-based', meaning you need to reach the other end of the level to get one of the hexidecimal numbers for the code

- It scrolls left/right instead of up/down. You start on the left and work your way right. You cannot scroll backward.

- There are 4 digits in the code, 0-9 and A-F. There are 6 Levels in total, 5 of which give you a random position in the code.

- The 6th level has the Missile Silo, and you must get through a minefield to get to it.

- If you don't reach the Missile Silo in time, or you cannot guess the launch code in time, the planet explodes, and the game ends.

- If you do enter the correct code, the game starts over, but harder :twisted:

- Two new types of enemies, aside from the Pillboxes, Jeeps, and Cruize Missiles found in the original

- want to put 'powerups' in the game, but not sure if I'll have the room.

The game is a work in progress. I was one of the people that download the game and I feel the games difficulty is a an issue. It is extremely hard even on the first level on Novice mode. Other people that tested the game had problems with that also. I don't know if this was the case with Countermeasure since I never own an Atari 5200 or played any Atari 5200 games. The graphics are good for an Atari 7800 game though.

The difficulty is being worked on the programmer, so this issue will be solved.

I don't know if the AtariAge store will have this game once it is finished. The store is still down.

My best advice is to be an Atariage member because the people that make the games actually sell the games to other Atariage members with there being a limited amount of cartridges being made before the Atariage store gets them sometimes.

http://www.nintendolife.com/forums/retro/new_atari_7800_game_is_being_worked_on
http://atariage.com/forums/topic/154189-failsafe-7800-wip/page-5?&amp;</desc>
    <releasedate>20100101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Bob DeCrescenzo</developer>
    <publisher>Atari Age</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Tank</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Fatal Run</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
In this post-apocalyptic driving/racing game you must travel to various towns delivering medicine, while on your way to a missile base which houses a rocket that can save the world. While driving through the 32 levels, you'll meet countless enemies who want to stop you from achieving your goal.

Your car boasts many weapons to help you out, including dynamite, rockets, oil slicks, smoke screens, and machine guns. You can also upgrade your vehicle within the city shops. Upgrading your gas tank provides better mileage while upgrading your bumper protects you during collisions. A password feature let's you continue where you left off.

Hints:

- Checkpoints -
Enter these in at the Title Screen to go to the specified checkpoints.
Eagle1: Checkpoint #1
Zebra: Checkpoint #2
Lynx: Checkpoint #3
Hornet8: Checkpoint #4
Dolphin: Checkpoint #5
Gorillas: Checkpoint #6
Turtle: Checkpoint #7

- Skip the First 28 Levels -
Enter TURTLE at the Title Screen.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/fatal-run</desc>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sculptured Software</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Racing - Cars</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Fight Night</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Fight Night is a boxing game in which players box 11 different opponents on the way to the final match with the champ, Bronx Bomber. Each boxer has unique strengths and weaknesses, along with one specialised "super punch".

There are four different modes of play; the single-player Main Event and the multi-player Tournament (on disk/cartridge versions only), and also Training and Sparring modes. Players can also create their own boxer, setting the appearance and abilities.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/fight-night</desc>
    <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Imagineering Inc/Absolute Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Sports - Boxing</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Food Fight</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
You play as Charley trying to eat an ice cream cone. But first you must avoid the chefs that are out to get you: Angelo, Zorba, Oscar, and Jacques. Avoid the food thrown at you by the chefs to get the cone. You can also throw your own food at the chefs to slow them down.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/food-fight</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Action - Arcade</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Froggie</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Frogger..... Splat!</desc>
    <releasedate/>
    <developer>Matthias Luedtke</developer>
    <publisher>Self-Published</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Galaga</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Galaga is a vertical arcade shooter from Namco. You control a space fighter at the bottom of the screen, scrolling left and right in order to avoid oncoming bombs and kamikaze attacks from alien invaders--and to fire your own missiles to fight back!

There are an infinite number of stages to progress through. Every third level is a "challenge stage" in which you have a free chance to shoot as many aliens as possible and rack up bonus points.

Certain aliens have tractor beams they can use to capture one of your ships. If that wasn't your last "life," you can try to shoot that alien down and recapture your ship, giving you two ships at once and doubling your firepower.

A summary screen appears when the game is over, giving you both your final score and you final "hit ratio"--the number of missiles fired, enemies destroyed, and the percentage of targets hit.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/galaga</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>GCC</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>GATO</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
The only known prototype was recently on display at Classic Gaming Expo.</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Ibid Inc</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Hat Trick</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Hat Trick is a two-on-two hockey game based on the 1984 coin-op of the same name. Each player controls a goalie and a skater. The object is to shoot the puck into the opposing teams goal. Each game lasts two minutes.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/hat-trick</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Ibid Inc</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Sports - Hockey</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Ikari Warriors</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
A conversion of the arcade game, Ikari Warriors is a vertically scrolling action game. One or two players fight their way through a variety of terrain, such as jungles, rivers, and ruins. Along the way different weapons can be found, including machine guns, grenades, and rocket launchers.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/ikari-warriors</desc>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Imagineering Inc/Absolute Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Impossible Mission</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
This altered version can be completed.

You play a secret agent on a quest to stop the evil Professor Elvin Atombender, who is believed to be tampering with national security computers. You must penetrate Atombender's stronghold, avoid his deadly robot creations, and acquire various pieces of a password to use in the main control room.

The robots, rooms, and puzzle pieces will be switched around when starting over which provides replay value.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/impossible-mission</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Man Development Corp/Computer Magic</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Jinks</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Jinks added a largely new concept to the Breakout type games,offering much freer paddle movement ( both horizontally and vertically), a horizontally scrolling screen and the ability to flip the triangular paddle as needed.

The objective is to survive on the planet Jinks - an exploration mission on this resource-rich planet has gone wrong. As hazards, there are objects that can destroy the paddle or make it smaller. There is also the ability to shake the screen if the ball is in a looping position.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/jinks</desc>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>US Gold</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Joust</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Joust was a popular arcade game that was created and released by Williams Electronics in 1982.

In the game, players take control of a knight with a lance who rides their flying ostrich (or stork, for Player 2) to do battle against computer-controlled evil knights who ride atop vultures. Players must flap their steed's wings to hit the enemy from a higher jousting point to destroy the vulture and its rider. Once the enemy has been hit, an egg falls to one of the platforms below. The heroic knights must destroy the eggs before they hatch and release new and increasingly more difficult knights. The three strengths of enemy knights are Bounder (red knight), Hunter (white knight) and Shadow Lord (blue knight).

These enemy knights are not the only challenge to be found in the game. Players must also contend with crumbling platforms, lava trolls who attempt to pull knights into the firey, and the dreaded "unbeatable"(?) pterodactyl.

Joust was novel for its time for being one of the few two-player simultaneous games in the arcade.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/joust</desc>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>GCC</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Jr. Pac-Man</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Jr. Pac-Man features gameplay similar to the original Pac-Man, but with a few changes. As Jr., you need to eat all of the dots in a maze without running into the four ghosts that are trying to get you. The maze is now much larger, and no longer fits on a single screen. The maze will scroll around to follow the action. From time to time a tasty bonus will bounce around the screen which can be eaten for extra points. There are tricycles, kites, drums, balloons, trains, root beers, and other bonuses that appear as the levels progress. When the bonus items bounce around the screen, any dots they touch will become larger and are now worth 50 points each instead of 10. However, one of these larger dots will cause Jr. Pac-Man to slow down greatly when he eats them making it more difficult to remain one step ahead of the ghosts which constantly pursue him! Located throughout the maze are power pellets; when Jr. eats one of these, the ghosts will temporarily turn blue and can now be eaten to earn even more points.

http://www.atariage.com/forums/topic/143026-reserve-list-for-jr-pac-man/page__p__1735440__hl__jr%20pac__fromsearch__1&amp;#entry1735440</desc>
    <releasedate>20090101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Bob DeCrescenzo</developer>
    <publisher>Self-Published</publisher>
    <genre>Maze</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Karateka</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
The evil Akuma has destroyed your homeland, killed many of your friends and kidnapped your Princess Mariko. Fortunately, you are skilled in Martial Arts, so your inevitable quest to reach Akuma's palace has a chance of success.

The game is viewed from the side and features a succession of increasingly-difficult opponents. All the standard karate kicks and punches are available to both you and your foes. The game's design was serious and realistic, and the game featured lots of cutscenes to develop the story.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/karateka</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Ibid Inc</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>VS Fighter</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Klax</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
An action/puzzle game, the object is to catch assorted color falling tiles and create rows, columns, or diagonals of a single color. Each level requires a different pattern to be made, and the tiles fall faster, more at a time, and in an increasing number of colors as the game progresses.

Hints:

Secret Levels

After you complete all 100 waves, you gain access to 3 secret levels. However, these levels are impossible to complete, and serve mostly as an easter egg.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/klax</desc>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>BlueSky Software</developer>
    <publisher>ResQsoft</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>KLAX</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
An action/puzzle game, the object is to catch assorted color falling tiles and create rows, columns, or diagonals of a single color. Each level requires a different pattern to be made, and the tiles fall faster, more at a time, and in an increasing number of colors as the game progresses.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/klax</desc>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>BlueSky Software</developer>
    <publisher>ResQsoft</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Kung-Fu Master</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
A conversion of the arcade game Kung Fu Master, which itself is loosely based on a movie. Mr. X has captured the pickpocket Sylvia, and it's up to Thomas, a kung-fu master who owns a restaurant, to get her back. She is located on the top floor of Mr. X's castle and Thomas will need to fight his way to the top. Of course, this won't be easy since each floor has many opponents to get past and an end of floor boss.

Thomas is able to move left and right, jump, duck and punch and kick. Enemy projectiles such as knives can be kicked in the air to rebound them towards the enemy. On the top floor resides Mr. X himself. Kung Fu is a side scrolling action game for one or two players, who alternate turns.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/kung-fu-master</desc>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Imagineering Inc/Absolute Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Absolute Entertainment</publisher>
    <genre>Beat 'em Up - Arcade</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Mario Bros.</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Mario and Luigi, the best plumbers in the world, have a real job on their hands. A host of characters have taken over the sewers, and the brothers must clear them out of the pipes.

The platform puzzle which first introduced Luigi to the world has both single and multiplayer action with two differing game types, but with the same objective. Crabs, turtles and fighter flies must be cleared out by jumping underneath the platform they sit on, then kicking them away. Each level is cleared when a set number of coins is collected.

For the two player mode, the first to collect the set amount of coins wins.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/mario-bros</desc>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ITDC</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Platformer - Arcade</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Mat Mania Challenge</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Tie up those wrestling boots and climb into the Atari Wrestling Federation Championship ring. Based on the Technos coin-op of 1985, Mat Mania challenge features two player head-to-head action, or a one player journey to the championship belt. Each match lasts three minutes.

The object is to either outscore, pin, or get your opponent counted out. You can perform such moves as the Overhead Slam or the Piledriver and many more; but your opponent has the same abilities.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/mat-mania-challenge</desc>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>BlueSky Software</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Sports - Wrestling</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Mean 18 Ultimate Golf</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Pebbele Beach and St. Andrews are two of the courses on offer in this golf simulation, released in the early years of 16-bit technology. The three-click control system was used, whereby the first click starts the swing, the second sets the power, and the third sets draw or fade.

Beginner and Expert difficulty options are given - the latter mode has more pronounced draw and fade effects, making the timing of the third click even more crucial. You can also choose between regular and professional tees - in the latter option the distance on the holes is longer, and the computer doesn't choose the best club automatically. Because long drives aren't a crucial aspect of many of the holes, the Begginer/Expert setting is a bigger factor on your likely scoring. A uniquie feature for the day was the course designer, which was quite versatile with practice.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/mean-18</desc>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>BlueSky Software</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Sports - Golf</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Meltdown</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Meltdown is an arcade action game similar to Reactor. On the screen you will see a representation of a nuclear reactor; numerous control rods are located in the center of the screen, with the reactor walls around the edges.

Inside the reactor are numerous (and dangerous) particles which will damage the control rods if they collide. Using the light gun, you need to shoot and destroy the various particles before the control rods are destroyed. As the control rods take damage, the walls of the reactor will slowly cave inward, decreasing the amount of space available. From time to time power crystals may appear; if shot, these will provide bonuses such as extra points, control rod repair, temporarily freeze the particles, more powerful shots, and more. The game ends when the control rods have been completely destroyed causing the reactor to meltdown.

Currently not working in A7800x (no lightgun support)

Hints:

- Expert level passwords -
1735: Level 10
3368: Level 11
2891: Level 12
1020: Level 13
7402: Level 14
2245: Level 15
6157: Level 16
1024: Level 17
5485: Level 18
4264: Level 19
8015: Level 2
7192: Level 20
8429: Level 3
5232: Level 4
0469: Level 5
9549: Level 6
3738: Level 7
2531: Level 8
3823: Level 9

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/meltdown</desc>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Light Gun</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Midnight Mutants</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
You play the part of Jimmy visiting Grampa on Halloween. Unfortunately, on this Halloween Dr. Evil has returned from the grave and captured Grampa in a pumpkin, and now you have to save him! Midnight Mutants is an action adventure game. As Jimmy you'll need to explore Grampa's mansion and the surrounding lands in order to find items which can be used to defeat enemies (including Dr. Evil) as well as safely reach new areas.

The lands have become cursed, however, and there will be many obstacles on your quest including killer bats, zombies, werewolves and more. Jimmy has two life meters, one for health and one for blood. Some creatures are poisonous on contact and reduce the blood meter, while others reduce the health meter. If either runs out, the game is over. Throughout the game, Grampa's spirit will be in contact with Jimmy and can occasionally provide clues or other useful information. The game features an isometric point of view, and in some larger areas the screen will scroll horizontally or vertically to follow the action. Good luck on your quest to save Grampa and survive this Halloween!

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/midnight-mutants</desc>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Radioactive Software/Pixcel Software Inc</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Missing in Action</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
A side scrolling adventure that was about 85% complete when canceled. The game is mostly playable with some later collision detection issues requiring cheats to get past. 

Chuck Norris...... 'Nuff Said!</desc>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sculptured Software</developer>
    <publisher>TNT Games</publisher>
    <genre>Beat 'em Up</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Motor Psycho</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
MotorPsycho is similar in feel to Pole Position, but with motorcycles substituting the cars. The object is to complete each race within the alloted time while dodging other motorcycles. Ramps strewn throughout the track allow the motorcycle to jump over obstacles and the other motorcyclists. You can shift between high and low gears, but there are no brakes. A player can customize their motorcycle by adjusting the "straighten" and "turn" response times before the race.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/motorpsycho</desc>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>BlueSky Software</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Racing - Motorcycles</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Ms. Pac-Man</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
In 1982, Midway and Namco created a sequel to the incredibly popular Pac-Man in the form of his girlfriend, Ms. Pac-Man. This sequel continued on the "eat the dots/avoid the ghosts" gameplay of the original game, but added new features to keep the title fresh.

Like her boyfriend, Ms. Pac-Man attempts to clear four various and challenging mazes filled with dots and ever-moving bouncing fruit while avoiding Inky, Blinky, Pinky and Sue, each with their own personalities and tactics. One touch from any of these ghosts means a loss of life for Ms. Pac-Man.

Ms. Pac-Man can turn the tables on her pursuers by eating one of the four Energizers located within the maze. During this time, the ghosts turn blue, and Ms. Pac-Man can eat them for bonus points (ranging from 200, 400, 800 and 1600, progressively). The Energizer power only lasts for a limited amount of time, as the ghost's eyes float back to their center box, and regenerate to chase after Ms. Pac-Man again.

Survive a few rounds of gameplay, and the player will be treated to humorous intermissions showing the growing romantic relationship between Pac-Man and Ms. Pac-Man, leading all the way up to the arrival of "Junior".

Hints:

1. Learn the ghost's characters and learn to use them to youradvantage.

2. Learn to group in you own ways. If you learn your own ways you knowhow to use them.

3. Develope methods that will aid you once you have a group.

4. Eat all four ghosts on every energizer. It is hard to clear verymany mazes past 25.

5. Don't get a "cruise elroy" until you have eaten all of theenergizers.

6. Be real patient. These techniques take a long time.

7.. Points are hard to come by later in the game. Get all the pointspossible early in the game.

8. Remember when you make a bad move the situation will probably showup again.

9. Never take your hands off the joystick even in the worstsituations. You may run through the ghost.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/ms-pac-man</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>GCC</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Maze</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Ninja Golf</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Ninja Golf is an arcade action game which combines a golf game with a side scrolling fighting game. You are a ninja, and your goal is to survive nine holes of ninja golf! On each of the holes, you alternate between the golf and action parts. First you hit the ball by selecting the direction and distance from the overhead view on the bottom of the screen; next you will need to run to the location your ball was hit while defending yourself from the many enemies.

Depending on the terrain you need to cross, various enemy ninjas, giant frogs, killer sharks, snakes, and other enemies will all get in your way. To eliminate the enemies, you can kick, punch, or use a throwing star. Several bonuses may be found from time to time; temporary invincibility, an extra life, health restoration, or a magic transport to the green may all appear on the screen. Once you have reached the green, you will need to defeat a fire breathing dragon which guards the hole. The nine hole course progressively increases in difficulty and features par 3, par 4, and par 5 holes.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/ninja-golf</desc>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>BlueSky Software</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Sports - Golf</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>One-on-One Basketball</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Control either Julius Irving or Larry Bird in front of a single basket, in a game of one on one. The user can select to play either to a certain score or for a certain amount of time. When on offense, the player can rotate to keep away from his rival, take a shot from a distance or move in to the basket for special up-close slam-dunks. When on defense, you can try to take your rival's ball or jump up to block a shot.

Particularly good set-ups get a slow-motion replay. You can even smash the glass on the backboard, which will send an irate janitor onto the court to clean up the mess.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/dr-j-and-larry-bird-go-one-on-one</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Man Development Corp/Computer Magic</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Sports - Basketball</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Pac-Man Collection!</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
This, as its name implies, is a collection of Pac-Man games, both the official versions and the unauthorized versions.

These are:

- Pac-Man: The original

- Puck-Man: The same as Pac-Man but with more difficult mazes.

- Hangly Man: A Pac-Man clone by Nittoh that has different mazes and sometimes the maze disappears.

- Ultra Pac-Man: Adds six new mazes to Pac-Man.

- Random Mazes: Chooses randomly from among the Pac-Man games

- Ms. Pac-Man: The original sequel

- Ms. Pac-Attack: The same as Ms. Pac-Man but with more difficult mazes

- Ms. Random Mazes: Chooses randomly from among the Ms. Pac-Man games

There are also options for 'Fast' and 'Plus'. 'Fast', obviously, speeds up the game play. 'Plus' adds elements to all games that were found in the unauthorized Bally Midway coin-op game Pac-Man Plus. These are:

- Bonus prize graphics are altered

- Bonus items act as an energizer pellet except the value of the monsters are doubled and the monsters are invisible during the energizer duration.

- Eating a standard energizer doesn't always turn all the monsters blue

- Eating a standard energizer may make the maze and dots disappear for the duration of the energizer.

- The maze colors are different to indicate 'Plus' mode

If you have the High Score Cartridge, it can save the high scores of each variation separately.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/pac-man-collection_</desc>
    <releasedate>20060101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher>AtariAge</publisher>
    <genre>Maze</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Pete Rose Baseball</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
This baseball game is licensed by former Cincinnati Reds player Pete Rose. It allows the player to play every position on the field. Different batting and pitching styles are available.

It has digitized voice and sound, and provides a variety of play options including One or Two-player action, season play or exhibition. In a somewhat ahead-of-its-time move, eight different perspectives are offered.

There are also some team management capabilities, as you select and order your team, and hire new players. This can run over ten seasons, making for one of the first Career modes.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/pete-rose-pennant-fever</desc>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Imagineering Inc/Absolute Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Absolute Entertainment</publisher>
    <genre>Sports - Baseball</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Pit Fighter</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
According to an internal document dated 5/14/93, this game was still very early in development. Atari's original cost for this title was $65,000 but they only paid $30,000 when the developer agreed to cancel the project without further payment.

Pit-Fighter was a 1990 arcade fighting game by Atari Games. It was revolutionary because it was the first fighting game ever to feature digitized characters using real life actors. The Atari 7800 version is a very early version of the game, and does not feature actual digitized sprite graphics like the arcade predecessor. While playable, there are issues with collision detection.

http://www.gooddealgames.com/inventory/Atari%207800.html</desc>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Imagitec Design</developer>
    <publisher>Atari Corporation</publisher>
    <genre>Beat 'em Up</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Planet Smashers</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Planet Smashers is a vertically scrolling shooter similar to Xevious. Power ups can be captured by destroying cargo ships. Power ups include improved weapons, shield restoration, and cloaking ability. Cargo ships also drop warp capsules that the player needs to collect in order to proceed to the level boss.

One difference in this game that sets it apart from others of the same type is the Earth Shield. Every time the player lets a ship go by unscathed the Earth Shield depletes a little. If the shield is destroyed, it's game over.

Hints:

- Unlock Secret Level and Level Select -
To get the secret level on the moon, you first have to beat the last level Mars. Then when you go back to the main menu, it will announce that you have unlocked level select. In level select you will have the new level on the moon.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/planet-smashers</desc>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sculptured Software - James V Zalewski</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Shoot 'em Up - Vertical</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Plutos</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Plutos is a long lost unreleased prototype developed by Tynesoft for the Atari 7800, and appears to be a loose port of the ST/Amiga game of the same name. The existence of Plutos has been known for some time, as a physical prototype has been in hands of a collector for years, but this prototype was known to be unstable and crash frequently. The source code for Plutos was discovered in 2008 and several 7800 enthusiasts were able to get it compiled and running properly on stock 7800 hardware. 

Plutos is a vertically oriented space shooter that features gameplay similar to Raiden. The game features six different levels, each with its own unique theme and boss. Only three of these levels are unique graphically--the other three are just color palette changes. Plutos offers one player as well as two player simultaneous modes, selectable with the left difficulty switch. Plutos also has features a unique weapons power-up system. There are three different types of weapons, each of which can be upgraded up to four times, as well as an invincibility power-up. The three different weapons are: Dual machine guns, spread gun, and energy gun. 

A partially compiled version of Plutos was discovered by Curt Vendel, and thanks to the efforts 7800 enthusiasts Robert DeCrescenzo, Mitchell Orman, and Eckhard Stolberg, made playable on 7800 hardware. It's a shame that Plutos was not released as it was obviously very close to completion and would have been a boost to the 7800 library.

http://www.atariage.com/software_page.html?SoftwareLabelID=2764</desc>
    <releasedate/>
    <developer>Tynesoft</developer>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Shoot 'em Up - Horizontal</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Pole Position II</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
In Pole Position II, based on the arcade sequel to Pole Position, you are again driving an F-1 racer in a timed qualifying run, trying to achieve the pole position. Then it is off to the race, in hopes of taking that top spot. The difference in Pole Position II and it's predecessor is that now you have four tracks top select from.

Hints:

1. Don't start out in high gear, as it will take your car longer to warm up.Instead, start in low gear and give your car a chance to get up to speed.Racing professionals usually shift gears around 160 MPH.  Shift intolow gear when you are going into a turn, and shift back into high gearwhen you come out.

2. If you crash into a roadside obstacle or another car, you will lose time.You won't lose the race, though, and you will be set to low gear automatically,so you can resume racing right away.

3. Watch out for puddles during the main race, they will slow you down.

4. Beginners should start with the Test Course and work their way up.

5. If you find that you are having trouble selecting a course with the joystick,use the SELECT button on the 7800 console instead.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/pole-position-ii</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>GCC</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Rampage</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
George, Lizzy and Ralph were just ordinary Americans, until an experiment went wrong, turning them into a Gorilla, Lizard and Werewolf respectively. Following this, the three of them plan to go round destroying buildings, and up to 3 human players can join in.

Smashing at the edges of the buildings for long enough will make them collapse. The police and military are after you, and will shoot at you, so try to destroy them (failing that, you can avoid the bullets). You will need to eat regularly, with things like plants on offer, to avoid shrinking back to being human

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/rampage</desc>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher>Activision</publisher>
    <genre>Action - Arcade</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Rampart</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Rampart is an unreleased Atari 7800 port of the Atari arcade game of the same name. Your goal in the arcade version of the game is to build up a castle using pieces to form a wall around your territory. After your castle is built, you then place cannons and use them to fire at enemy ships or another player's castle. After each round you then have an opportunity to rebuild your castle before the next round begins. 

Unfortunately, the 7800 port of Rampart that is currently available is in an early state and not complete in terms of gameplay or graphics, which is immediately obvious by the lack of a proper title screen. Rampart requires a two-button 7800 joystick. You can select difficulty and number of players, including one player, two players, team or competition modes. Gameplay consists of shooting the enemy targets, which appear as "NME" graphics. The left joystick button fires your normal weapon. The right fire button will destroy all enemies onscreen. If you choose a two player game (team or competition), both players can shoot at enemy targets. There are several different playfield backgrounds depending on the game type selected, or if you play additional games. 

A partially compiled version of Rampart was discovered by Curt Vendel, and thanks to the efforts 7800 enthusiasts Robert DeCrescenzo, Mitchell Orman, and Eckhard Stolberg, made playable on 7800 hardware. Internal Atari memos from 1993 mention that the game is almost finalized, so a more complete version of the game must exist somewhere.

http://www.atariage.com/software_page.html?SoftwareLabelID=2766</desc>
    <releasedate/>
    <developer>Imagitec Design</developer>
    <publisher>Atari Corporation</publisher>
    <genre>Arcade</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>RealSports Baseball</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Baseball is an action game which can be played by two players or one player against the computer. The game allows you to bunt the ball or try for a homerun, steal bases, and throw several types of pitches from a fast ball to a curve ball. 

Several game variations are included which allow you to select whether the home or visiting team is at bat first, and whether or not a player can swing only at pitches that are a strike, or they can swing at any pitch.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/realsports-baseball</desc>
    <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Sports - Baseball</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Rescue on Fractalus</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
In 2004 Curt Vendel of AtariMuseum.com uncovered several Atari 7800 prototypes, including the unreleased game Rescue on Fractalus. While the game is not complete, it is fairly far along, runs pretty smoothly, and can be played with the excellent MESS emulator. To start the game after firing it up, press "R" (Reset) in MESS. There is a glitch in the emulation right now with the rendering of your view outside the cockpit, but we expect this will be fixed in an upcoming release of MESS.

http://www.atariage.com/software_page.html?SoftwareLabelID=2693</desc>
    <releasedate/>
    <developer>GCC</developer>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Action - First Person</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Robotron: 2084</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
You are a mutant human, who by some freak of nature has the ability to shoot energy pulses from his body in eight different directions! Your job is simple: save humanity from their own creation -- the ROBOTRONS! The gameplay is pretty unique for the time.

You can move and fire in any of eight directions. You get thrown in a room with various evil baddies strewn about, you've got to kill all the robots while at the same time finding some way to grab humans and avoid death.

Hints:

1. If you're trying to get big points, the Brain Waves are a great way to do so.  There are a lot of humans onscreen during the Brain Waves, so kill off all but one of the enemies, and then go after all the humans.  Make sure you don't kill 
the last remaining enemy or the wave will end and you'll forfeit your big opportunity!

2. The only hazards to the humans are Hulks and Brains, so try to focus on clearing out most of the enemies first before going after them.

3. It's best to avoid Hulks rather than shooting at them, unless you have absolutely no choice, since even with your rapid fire, they don't move far, and there's a good chance you can get surrounded while trying to move them out of your way, or accidentally cause them to kill a human.

4. If you're playing with two joysticks, try to find a way to hold them down so that they don't move around when you're trying to play with them.  Remember that you can use Atari 2600 joysticks, which are smaller and easier to use.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/robotron-2084</desc>
    <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>GCC</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Arcade</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Santa Simon</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Santa, a reindeer, a Christmas tree and a snowman will signal you, in a pattern order. Using the joystick, you must repeat the same pattern. See how many increasingly long patterns you can master before you make a mistake.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/santa-simon</desc>
    <releasedate>20070101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Matthias Luedtke</developer>
    <publisher>AtariAge</publisher>
    <genre>Board Game</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Scrapyard Dog</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
In Scrapyard Dog you play the role of Louie, the junkyard guy, who's companion Scraps has been dognapped by the dastardly Mr. Big. Louie has bombs and cans at his disposal to use against the enemies, which include gangsters, rats, and mice. He can also use shields to protect himself on route to the sixteen checkpoints in the game. Louie must reach each checkpoint in a certain amount of time in order to save Scraps.

Hints:

- Change the background music -
Switch the Left Difficulty switch left and right to change the game's background music.

- Three extra cans -
To get three extra cans, get to Level 2 (Eisenhower Lane). You will be standing under a ledge. Go to the end of the ledge, but do NOT go on to the next ledge. If part of your head is still under the ledge, jump up three times to get the extra cans.

- Completing Level 2-3 -
There is a large gap in level 2-3 that Louie must cross. Jump on the middle sewer pipe, then jump on the pipe to the left. Walk to the left edge of this pipe and, then run to the right. Continue running until Louie reaches the edge of the third, and lowest, pipe in the series. Then, jump to cross over the sludge gap. 

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/scrapyard-dog</desc>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>BlueSky Software</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Platformer</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Sentinel</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Sentinel is a side scrolling action game. Several worlds have fallen victim of an alien attack, and you need to free them. To do this, a glowing orb called the Sentinel has been sent which can absorb the alien energy. As the Sentinel floats above the various, scrolling landscapes, you need to protect it from attacks by using the light gun to destroy enemies and enemy fire. If you don't destroy an enemy, it will deplete the Sentinels energy supply which will eventually destroy it.

There are four levels of increasing difficulty, each with a large boss at the end. To help out on your mission, several bonuses may be encountered from time to time; increased firepower and energy can be acquired when you shoot the bonus capsules that appear. Three levels of difficulty are available.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/sentinel</desc>
    <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Imagineering Inc/Absolute Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Light Gun</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Sirius</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Sirius is a long lost unreleased prototype developed by Tynesoft for the Atari 7800, possibly a port of the 1990 Amiga game Sirius 7. Sirius' existence has been known for some time, as a physical prototype has been in hands of a collector for years, but this prototype was known to be unstable and crash frequently. The source code for Sirius was discovered in 2008 and several 7800 enthusiasts were able to get it compiled and running properly on stock 7800 hardware. 

Sirius is a horizontally oriented space shooter that will feel right at home to those familiar with games such as Gradius and R-Type. The game consists of four different levels, each with its own unique theme and boss. Sirius deftly demonstrates what the 7800 hardware is capable of and compares favorably with NES and Sega Master System games of the time. Unfortunately, Sirius is aggravatingly difficult and will require much practice and patience to succeed through all four levels. 

Sirius is a single player game only. The difficulty level (easy and hard) can be selected via the left difficulty switch. Sirius has several different types of weapons power-ups. The first is a "ghost ship" that follows you and fires when you fire. Other power-ups include rapid fire guns and rapid fire plus spread fire. You can pick up one extra of each power-up type for reserve so that when you are killed you won't be quite so vulnerable. There are also diamonds that you can pick up but they don't seem to do much other than reward you 300 points. 

A partially compiled version of Sirius was discovered by Curt Vendel, and thanks to the efforts 7800 enthusiasts Robert DeCrescenzo, Mitchell Orman, and Eckhard Stolberg, made playable on 7800 hardware. It's a shame that Sirius was not released as it was obviously very close to completion and would have been a boost to the 7800 library.

http://www.atariage.com/software_page.html?SoftwareLabelID=2765</desc>
    <releasedate/>
    <developer>Tynesoft</developer>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Shoot 'em Up - Horizontal</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Snow Day: Jr. Pac-Man</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
No information online about this Jr. Pac-Man hack.  ~Rx</desc>
    <releasedate/>
    <developer>Jeff Wierer</developer>
    <publisher>Unpublished</publisher>
    <genre>Maze</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Space Duel</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Space Duel is a port to the Atari 7800 of the third generation of Asteroids-style shooters from Atari, following on the heels of Asteroids and Asteroids Deluxe. Unlike Asteroids Deluxe, Space Duel is a more radical departure from its predecessor, featuring a wide variety of colorful geometric shapes you must destroy, and several new types of enemies each with unique behaviors you have to contend with in order to stay alive! In addition, there is a bonus round where players can earn extra points. Like many great games, Space Duel is easy to learn, but takes time and practice to master.

Space Duel features several two-player variations including Competition Space Duel where you compete against another player for points (and your shots destroy the other player!), and Team Space Duel where you and another player share reserve ships and don't need to worry about friendly fire. Space Duel comes to life on the Atari 7800 thanks to the efforts of Robert DeCrescenzo, who extensively modified the original version of Asteroids to add all the unique Space Duel gameplay elements, graphics and sounds!

http://www.atariage.com/software_page.html?SoftwareLabelID=2770</desc>
    <releasedate>20070101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Bob DeCrescenzo</developer>
    <publisher>AtariAge</publisher>
    <genre>Action - Arcade</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Space Invaders 7800 (Beta)</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
This is an early beta of the game.  

Try and find the final release of the game. (crc F2699E24,A78E5587,9C3086EB)</desc>
    <releasedate>20070101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Bob DeCrescenzo</developer>
    <publisher>Self-Published</publisher>
    <genre>Action - Arcade</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Space Invaders 7800</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Space Invaders now exists for the 7800 :)

http://www.atariage.com/forums/topic/127729-space-invaders-7800/</desc>
    <releasedate>20070101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Bob DeCrescenzo</developer>
    <publisher>Self-Published</publisher>
    <genre>Action - Arcade</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Star Wars 7800</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Xevious game with a Star Wars theme.  Play as the Millennium Falcon!</desc>
    <releasedate>20070101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Action - Arcade</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Summer Games</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Summer Games allows up to eight players to compete in a series of summer themed Olympic events. The gameplay is similar to the other entries in Epyx "games" series. Each player can choose a country to represent, and then takes turns competing in various events to see who will win the gold medal!

The game allows you to compete in all of the events sequentially, choose a few events, choose just one event, or practice an event. The events available vary slightly depending on the platform, and may include:

Pole vault; Platform diving; 4x400 meter relay; 100 meter dash; Gymnastics; Freestyle swimming; Skeet shooting; 100 meter freestyle; Rowing

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/summer-games</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Man Development Corp/Computer Magic</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Sports - Competitive Events</genre>
    <players>8</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Super Huey UH-1X</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Super Huey UH-IX is a helicopter simulation game. You are the pilot of the experimental helicopter UH-1XA and you need to test it out in several game modes. In the flight school mode, you can learn how to fly. The computer will guide you through takeoff, flight, and landing.

In reality mode, you will need to fly a mission to locate and bomb an enemy base and return home safely. The last mode is arcade mode where you have an unlimited amount of ammo to try and shoot down as many enemy aircraft as possible. The game is played from a first person view of the cockpit which is complete with radar and various instruments to help you fly.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/super-huey-uh-ix</desc>
    <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Cosmi Corporation</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Flight Simulator</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Super Pac-Man</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Super Pac-Man... instead of gobbling up dots, Pac is required to eat fruit and prizes, such as apples, bunches of bananas, doughnuts, hamburgers, fried eggs, ears of corn, sneakers, pieces of cakes, raspberries, limes, cups of coffee, mushrooms, Galaxians, bells and shamrocks. Most of these items are hidden in passages that have locked doors at either entrance, and in order to unlock the doors, Pac needs to eat the key that is closest to the passage that he wishes to unlock. As usual, ghosts will keep chasing Pac around the maze until he has lost all his lives. However, Pac can enter the warp tunnels at either side of the maze to lose the ghosts quickly.

There are two types of power pellets in the maze: green and yellow. Yellow power pellets cause ghosts to turn blue, allowing Pac to eat them for points, whereas green ones cause Pac to enlarge and will also cause the ghosts to become much thinner and wider, allowing him to fly over them. He can also break open the doors without the need of keys. The effects of the pellets, unfortunately, only lasts for a number of seconds. During the time that he is enlarged, a flashing star will appear besides two boxes that are located in the middle of the maze. The first box will display the current fruit or prize, and the other will display a rotating selection of them. If Pac manages to eat the star when they match, there will be a large bonus score.

Occasionally, after three or more stages, there will be a bonus stage where Pac automatically gets enlarged. The object of these stages is to eat everything in the maze before the time runs out, and during these stages, there will be no ghosts to pursue him.

http://www.atariage.com/forums/topic/132832-7800-super-pac-man-i-found-the-bug/page__p__1601218__hl__super%20pac__fromsearch__1&amp;#entry1601218</desc>
    <releasedate>20080101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Bob DeCrescenzo</developer>
    <publisher>Self-Published</publisher>
    <genre>Arcade - Maze</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Super Skateboardin'</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Super Skateboardin' is a game where a young skateboarder is hired by his dad's company to do what he does best, Skateboard. Your job is to navigate the many rooms of the factory and turn off all the electrical equipment in 15 minutes, or else the electricity bill will skyrocket. Your wage is based on how fast you complete the task, and you need that money to enter the Skateboarding Championship. Super Skateboardin' is a straightforward game from the designer of Pitfall!, David Crane.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/super-skateboardin</desc>
    <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Imagineering Inc/Absolute Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Absolute Entertainment</publisher>
    <genre>Sports - Skateboard</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Tank Command</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Tank Command is a vertically scrolling action game. You control a tank on a mission to capture the enemy flag as well as earn as many points as possible. To do this, you will need to blast your way through their defenses on three levels of increasing difficulty. Blocking your progress are enemy tanks, pillboxes, missiles, jeeps, infantry, huts, and more, all of which earn you points when destroyed.

Your tank is equipped with a limited amount of fuel and ammo, however it can be replenished occasionally by collecting the bonus icons when they appear on the screen. If you can make it past all of the obstacles and capture the flag, then you win the game!

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/tank-command</desc>
    <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Froggo Games</developer>
    <publisher>Froggo Games</publisher>
    <genre>Action - Arcade</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Title Match Pro Wrestling</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Title Match is a wrestling game which can be played by one or two players. There are four different wrestlers you can choose from, and two modes of gameplay (one on one, or tag team). Each wrestler can kick, punch, and perform several moves such as the airplane spin, body slam, power lift, and more. Using the available moves you need to deplete your opponents energy and pin him for three counts (though be careful, as some of the more powerful moves also use up a bit of your own energy).

If your opponents energy is low enough and you successfully pin him that will count as a fall, and the best out of three falls will win the match!

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/title-match-pro-wrestling</desc>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Imagineering Inc/Absolute Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Absolute Entertainment</publisher>
    <genre>Sports - Wrestling</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Tomcat: The F-14 Fighter Simulator</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Become a F-14 Naval Aviator undergoing seek and destroy missions while dodging and gunning enemy bogeys in deadly dogfights with your 20mm cannon and air-to-air missiles.

You cockpit comes with state of the art technology, courtesy of the U.S. Air Force: Display and main computer, Bogey Alert Indicator, G-Force Indicator, Electronic Counter Measures, and a Cannon Overheat Indicator (yes, it can overheat!)...and if your feeling up to it, give the ol'bird a boost to Mach 1.0!

The gameplay like other simulation games consists of taking off, flying, combat and landing. Though most of the gameplay focuses around dogfighting with enemy bogeys (dodging missiles). In addition to that, there are also night-flying missions that add difficulty due to limited vision.

Taking off and landing however, also required additional skill as your doing it on the USS Enterprise (No relation to Star Trek), not on your standard airstrip. Pay attention to the F.D. officer as your preparing to take off (since he's the boss when it comes to this stuff...and try no to run over him...yet).

Your weaponry consists of a M 61 Machine Gun and 3 different AIM Missiles (AIM 7, 9, 54) each packed with 15 missiles (that's a lot of missiles!).

After each mission you will receive a Mission Rating which is based on your flying skill, number of bogey kill and number of weapons fired.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/dan-kitchens-tomcat-the-f-14-fighter-simulator</desc>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Imagineering Inc/Absolute Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Absolute Entertainment</publisher>
    <genre>Flight Simulator</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Touchdown Football</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
A very capable football simulation, given the year and technology. Call the plays, then run them using the keyboard or joystick. Digitized voices enhance the game, including the crowd, calling the numbers, and referee's calls.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/touchdown-football</desc>
    <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Imagineering Inc/Absolute Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Sports - Football</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Tower Toppler</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
You play a small green guy who needs to blow up eight towers, because their presence is somehow poisoning the water of planets which could potentially be ideal colonies. Unfortunately you need to get to the top of these towers to blow them up.

You make your way up to the top of the tower via walkways around the outside of the towers. You need to jump over, kick, and run from various enemies in your journey to the top. Most vertical movement is achieved by jumping onto moving ledges at the right moment.

The game was considered revolutionary in its time for its graphic technique. As the main character walked around the outside of the tower, the character was fixed in the middle of the screen while the tower itself rotated. This gave it a pseudo-3D effect.

Towers are linked together via a voyage through the sea in your trusty MK.7 submarine. This plays out as a side-scrolling collect-'em-up in which bonus points can be obtained.

Hints:

- Level Select -
Switch the Left Difficulty switch to the left while you're playing the game to show the other towers. Switch it back to the right to choose the tower that is currently displayed.

- Game Completed Message -
Enable the LEVEL SELECT code that is mentioned above. Go back into level 1, and beat level 1. After beating level 1, the "GAME COMPLETED" message will appear.

- Unlimited Lives -
Use the Level Select code to choose the tower before the one you wish to have infinite lives in. Once in that tower, lose all of your lives. After this move the left difficulty switch to the left. This should be done after you lose your last life, but before the game over screen. The next tower should then appear. Move the switch back to the right for unlimited lives.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/tower-toppler</desc>
    <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>US Gold</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Tubes</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Tubes is a new Atari 7800 homebrew being written by Bruce Tomlin. Fans of Tetris-style games will enjoy this one, which has blocks of different types of "tubes" (or pipes) falling from above. Your objective is to place the different tube pieces in order to make contiguous sections of pipe using the connectors available on each side of your playfield. When you create a section of pipe that is closed on both ends, those pipes will then disappear, making room for new pipe. Bombs will also periodically fall, allowing you a chance to clear poorly placed pipes.

http://www.atariage.com/development_page.html?InDevelopmentID=91</desc>
    <releasedate/>
    <developer>Bruce Tomlin</developer>
    <publisher>Self-Published</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Wasp!</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
It's the Enchanted Land's annual Mushroom Soup Festival.  While out in the woods collecting mushrooms you stumble across a nest of Giant Killer Wasps.  With no giants to kill they make a wasp line for... YOU!

~From the back of the box</desc>
    <releasedate>20090101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Mark Ball</developer>
    <publisher>Self-Published</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Water Ski</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
In Water Ski you are water skiing on the Pharonna River. You control both the boat and skier in this vertically scrolling action game. Your goal is to reach the finish line before time runs out and also to earn as many points as possible. The river is quite dangerous, and features many twists and turns along with rocks, logs and other obstacles.

For bonus points there are numerous ramps located throughout the river which your skier can jump over (and if you can manage to ski over every ramp on the level, you'll earn even more points!). You start the game with four skiers, and the game ends when all of you skiers have crashed.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/water-ski</desc>
    <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Froggo Games</developer>
    <publisher>Froggo Games</publisher>
    <genre>Sports - Water Skiing</genre>
    <players>1</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Winter Games</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Another in the series of Epyx Olympic sports games. Compete in many different sporting events like: ski jump, Hot Dog, Biathlon, Bobsled, Free Skating, Figure Skating and more.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/winter-games</desc>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Man Development Corp/Computer Magic</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Sports - Competitive Events</genre>
    <players>8</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Xenophobe</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
Xenos. The very name strikes fear into every colonist's heart. A distress call is received from space stations orbiting your homeworld, then silence. A single ship escapes, piloted by a battered man who tells the tale of pods that hatch into acid-spitting Xenos.

A small band of engineers has been dispatched to combat the Xeno threat before it takes over all the space stations and, eventually, your homeworld. Assemble your band of engineers and fight the Xenos on each station, striving to either clear it or abandon it. You start out with a standard issue laser, but can pick up additiona weapons as you find them, including Phasers, Lightning Rifles, Poofer guns, and bombs.

Xenophobe was originally an arcade coin-op by Bally/Midway, released in 1987. Gameplay premise and setting is heavily inspired/influenced by the movie Aliens.

Unplayable on A7800x.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/xenophobe</desc>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>BlueSky Software</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Xevious</name>
    <path/>
    <image/>
    <video/>
    <marquee/>
    <desc>
It is discovered that the actual aliens on earth are human beings, and the ruthless Xevions want their planet back; but without us. Our only defense is the prototype Solvalou Fighter Plane. With this plane we can fight the deadly Domogram Rovers; the Toroid Patrol Fleets and the Zoshi Death Squads.

Xevious is a vertically scrolling shooter based on the 1982 coin-op of the same name. It was innovative in that it was the first vertically scrolling shooter to feature dual-level attacks; both ground and air.

http://www.mobygames.com/game/atari-7800/xevious</desc>
    <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>GCC</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <genre>Shoot 'em Up - Vertical</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
</gameList>
